Guide to the Robert Giard Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- February 2005 Acquisition, 1972-2002; 1; 50.06; (270 boxes)
  - Oversize Photographs (16" x 20")
    - Nudes
      - With Figurative Elements
        - Man with Nude Drawing, 1981 (Box 260)
          N# 0099b
        - (seated male nude with illuminated female torso), 1980 (Box 260)
          N# 0100a
        - (male nude posed on sideboard, table set with plates in foreground), undated (Box 260)
          N# 0101b
        - (male nude reclining, framed portrait of eyes in background), undated (Box 260)
          N# 0102a
        - (male nude posed with Christmas tree-Kevin), undated (Box 260)
          N# 0103a
        - Man with Portrait of Rimbaud (Douglas Ball), 1980 (Box 260)
          N# 0104a
        - Grapes, 1978 (Box 260)
          N# 0105a
        - (man on bed, toy robot at right), 1989 (Box 260)
          N# 0106a
        - Man with a Mask, 1979 (Box 260)
          N# 0107
        - Jon and Arthur, 1979 (Box 260)
          N# 0108a
        - (male nude and classical relief), undated (Box 261)
          N# 0109
        - Man with Flamingos, 1979 (Box 261)
          N# 0110a
        - (male nude posed in corner, mirrors at right, media equipment at left), undated (Box 261)
          N# 0111a
        - (male nude leaning on sofa, harp in foreground), undated (Box 261)
          N# 0112a
        - (male nude posed with wrought iron ornament), undated (Box 261)
          N# 0113a
        - (male nude, rear view, hand on wicker torso), 1990 (Box 261)
          N# 0114a
        - Man in Seagull Bathroom (Jonathan Silin), 1979 (Box 261)
          N# 0115a
        - Aquatic Bathroom (Jonathan Silin), 1979 (Box 261)
          N# 0116
        - Man Among Movie Stars, 1978 (Box 261)
          N# 0117
        - (male nude seated in painting studio-Newt McMahon), 1981 (Box 261)
          N# 0118
        - Man in a Headdress, 1978 (Box 261)
          N# 0119a
        - (male nude standing behind sliding doors-Herb Spears?), undated (Box 261)
          N# 0120a
        - Man with Fashion Posters, 1981 (Box 261)
          N# 0121c
        - Man with Figured Painting, 1977 (Box 261)
          N# 0122b
        - (male nude with classical relief and vase), undated (Box 261)
          N# 0123a
  - Photographs (11" x 14")
    Organized into nine subseries: Portraits, India, Landscapes, Nudes, Balloon Series, Neo-Classical Series, Piano Series, Beach Sequence, and Assorted Nudes.
    - Portraits
      - Back of Child's Head, 1976 (Box 262)
      - George Stambolian with Cape, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0177
      - George Stambolian with Cape profile right, undated (Box 262)
      - Marge Caggiano with butterfly, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0179
      - John Cromwell Seated, 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0180
      - Mimi Black with vaccum cleaner, 1979 (Box 262)
        P# 0181
      - Man with sparkler, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0182
      - Richard Dulong with Howdy Doodey, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0183
      - Woman at table, 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0184
      - Woman/Camera/Cigarette, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0185
      - Seated man with cactus, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0186
      - Portrait of George Whitney #1, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0187
      - Portrait of George Whitney #2, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0188a
      - Arthur Tress with Goggles, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0190
      - Pool player, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0191
      - Woman in a Snood (Erma Brownfield), 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0192
      - Man in turtleneck, 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0193
      - Christanne with scarf, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0194
      - Hands w/dough, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0197
      - Hands w/pizza, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0198
      - Daisy Klingman in Highchair, 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0201
      - Boy at Billiard Table, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0203
      - Mother and Infant, 1975 (Box 262)
        P# 0204c
      - Girl with Bouquet and Bandaide, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0205
      - Two School Boys, 1974 (Box 262)
        P# 0207
      - Bearded man by balcony, 1979 (Box 262)
        P# 0270
      - Man sitting cross legged on bed, 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0210
      - Man reclining on bed, 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0211
      - Man with a hairy chest, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0212
      - Man on couch with dog, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0213
      - Man on couch with dog #2, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0214
      - Woman with knitted hat from back, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0216
      - Man with tennis racket, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0217
      - Summer Portrait, 1975 (Box 262)
        P# 0218
      - Woman's long hair with flowers, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0274a
      - Pool Player, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0220a
      - Pool Player #2, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0221
      - Boy in a Popeye Shirt, 1975 (Box 262)
        P# 0222
      - Man in Ski Mask, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0223
      - Boy with Swim Wings, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0224
      - Apple Pie & Tee Shirt, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0229
      - Annette, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0230a
      - Man at Window, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0231a
      - Barebacked Man, 1979 (Box 262)
        P# 0232
      - Young man standing w/unicycle, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0233
      - Formal Portrait (Barry Klingman), 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0234a
      - Portrait of Richard Zellins (Man in His Loft), 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0235a
      - Dianna Lindly & Val Schaffner, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0236a
      - Man Through Vertical Hole, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0237
      - Woman Through Vertical Hole, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0238
      - Man & Woman with Backdrop, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0239
      - Man with Springs, 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0240a
      - Portrait of Christianne Drabbe, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0241
      - Kneeling Man & Mirror, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0242
      - Seated Man Looking into Mirror, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0243a
      - Seated Man Looking into Camera, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0244a
      - Portrait of Sydney Butchkes #2, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0245
      - Daisy Klingman as a Teenager #1, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0246
      - Daisy Klingman as a Teenager #2, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0248
      - Man in Mickey Mouse Tee Shirt, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0249
      - Portrait of Newton McManon, 1977 (Box 262)
        P# 0250
      - Man with a Kite, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0251
      - Dead Fawn, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0252
      - Boy on the Rocks, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0253
      - Boy in a Mickey Mouse Shirt, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0254
      - Exhausted Cyclyist, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0255
      - Sign Man, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0256
      - Man with Child on Shoulders, undated (Box 262)
        P# 0257
      - Mother and Baby in a White Suit, 1975 (Box 262)
        P# 0258
      - Man Looking Under Hood, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0260
      - An Artist and His Work #2, 1976 (Box 262)
        P# 0267
      - Group of Boys at Billiard Table, 1978 (Box 262)
        P# 0275
      - Californian, 1976 (Box 263)
        P# 0195c
      - Horse, 1974 (Box 263)
        P# 0196b
      - Richard Dulong in Bomber Jacket, 1976 (Box 263)
        P# 0199a
      - Baby in a Stroller, 1975 (Box 263)
        P# 0200b
      - Man w/White Glove and Knitted Cap, 1976 (Box 263)
        P# 0206a
      - Boy in a Winter Parka, 1974 (Box 263)
        P# 0208b
      - Man under VW Hood, 1975 (Box 263)
        P# 0209a
      - Boy with Prehistoric Man, 1975 (Box 263)
        P# 0215a
      - Man in Undershirt, 1975 (Box 263)
        P# 0219b
      - Hand and Glove, 1976 (Box 263)
        P# 0225
      - Sailor, 1974 (Box 264)
        P# 0226a
      - Boy with a Frisbee, 1976 (Box 264)
        P# 0226b
      - The Children and a Horse, 1975 (Box 264)
        P# 0227a
      - Morning Coffee, 1975 (Box 264)
        P# 0228a
      - Trunks, 1975 (Box 264)
        P# 0259a
      - Play Group, 1975 (Box 264)
        P# 0261a
      - Windbreaker (Jim Hickey), 1976 (Box 264)
        P# 0262b
      - Winter Booties, 1976 (Box 264)
        P# 0263a
      - Helmet, 1975 (Box 264)
        P# 0264a
      - Woman with Her Hair in a Towel, 1975 (Box 264)
        P# 0265b
      - An Artist and His Work #1, 1976 (Box 265)
        P# 0268a
      - Pt. Lobos #2, 1976 (Box 265)
        P# 0269a
      - Black Girl with a White Doll, 1976 (Box 265)
        P# 0273a
      - Lamp & Head, 1976 (Box 265)
        P# 0276
      - Glass of Milk, 1975 (Box 265)
        P# 0276b
      - Billy Cooking at Stove, 1976 (Box 265)
        P# 0277
      - Pt. Lobos, undated (Box 265)
        P# 0278
    - India (GQ magazine assignment)
      - [untitled], 1970s (Box 266)
        L# 0048
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0049
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0050
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0051
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0052
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0053
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0054
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0055
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0056
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0057
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0058
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0059
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0060
      - [untitled] (Box 266)
        L# 0061
    - Landscape
      - (netting over garden), 1979 (Box 266)
        L# 0117
      - (fences and trellis), undated (Box 266)
        L# 0118
      - Arbor and Tree, 1977 (Box 266)
        L# 0120
      - (deck and trellis), 1979 (Box 266)
        L# 0121b
      - (two children in driveway, one flying kite), 1978 (Box 266)
        L# 0122a
      - (car, garage, boat), 1978 (Box 266)
        L# 0123
      - (clothesline carousel in backyard), undated (Box 266)
        L# 0124
      - Rounded Hedge, 1976 (Box 266)
        L# 0125
      - Hedge, 1975 (Box 266)
        L# 0126
      - Trees in Front of a House, 1973 (Box 266)
        L# 0127
      - Garage, 1976 (Box 266)
        L# 0128
      - Plant, 1976 (Box 266)
        L# 0129
      - (car in driveway, horse at left), 1977 (Box 266)
        L# 0130
      - Sky, Hedge & Lawn, 1976 (Box 266)
        L# 0131
      - (swans at edge of pond), 1978 (Box 266)
        L# 0133
      - (sidewalk, fence, tree at left, house at right), 1979 (Box 266)
        L# 0134
      - (mirror outside reflecting tree and sky), 1978 (Box 266)
        L# 0136
      - (small, leafless bush in front of larger hedges), undated (Box 266)
        L# 0137
      - (porch, latticework, dappled sunlight), 1978 (Box 266)
        L# 0138
      - (wooden tower covered in vines), 1977 (Box 266)
        L# 0139
      - (side of hill with erosion guards), 1977 (Box 266)
        L# 0140
      - (boat house doors), 1978 (Box 266)
        L# 0141
      - (birdhouse, fence), 1978 (Box 266)
        L# 0142
      - (birdhouse, birdbath, and garden ornaments), 1979 (Box 266)
        L# 0143
      - (two carousel horses), 1979 (Box 266)
        L# 0144
      - Garage Door, 1976 (Box 266)
        L# 0145
      - Garage Roof, 1977 (Box 266)
        L# 0147
      - White House, 1977 (Box 266)
        L# 0148
      - Pool and Scottee, 1975 (Box 266)
        L# 0149
      - (base of pole), undated (Box 266)
        L# 1052
      - Effigy #1 (Dog and Scarecrow), 1975 (Box 266)
        L# 0150
      - Effigy with Dog #2, 1975 (Box 266)
        L# 0151
    - Nudes
      - Nude with Caged Dolls, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0124
      - (male nude with mustache in bathroom), undated (Box 266)
        N# 0125
      - Figure on the Stairs, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0126
      - Jonathan in Marge's Bathroom No. 2, 1979 (Box 266)
        N# 0127c
      - (rearview of male, arms wrapped around back, painting in background), undated (Box 266)
        N# 0128
      - Black Torso, 1984 (Box 266)
        N# 0129d
      - Jonathan in Marge's Bathroom No. 3, 1979 (Box 266)
        N# 0130a
      - George Stambolian (face down on bed), undated (Box 266)
        N# 0131a
      - Man in a Plastic Bag, 1977 (Box 266)
        N# 0132a
      - (torso at left, painted bird at right-Jonathan Silin in bathroom), 1979 (Box 266)
        N# 0133a
      - Man in a Robe, 1977 (Box 266)
        N# 0134
      - Jonathan in a Bathroom, No. 1, 1979 (Box 266)
        N# 0135a
      - Nude with a Weight, 1977 (Box 266)
        N# 0136
      - Nude Torso with Cycle & Helmet, 1977 (Box 266)
        N# 0137a
      - (male nude wearing snorkel mask seated in bathroom), 1979 (Box 266)
        N# 0138a
      - Motorcycle Nude with Hand on Back, 1977 (Box 266)
        N# 0139a
      - Artist and Model (self-portrait in mirror with Jonathan Silin), 1979 (Box 266)
        N# 0140
      - (standing male nude wearing glasses, leaning on outstretched hand), undated (Box 266)
        N# 0141
      - Man with a Pillow over His Head, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0142a
      - Richard in the Shower No. 3: Drying Himself, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0143
      - Richard in the Shower No. 8: Washing His Foot, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0144a
      - Richard in the Shower No. 7: With Leg on Edge of Tub, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0145a
      - Richard in the Shower No. 6: Holding Towel, Leg Raised, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0146a
      - (male nude with foot in sink-Jonathan Silin), undated (Box 266)
        N# 0147
      - (male standing in doorway with painting in background), undated (Box 266)
        N# 0148
      - (crouching male nude holding onto mirror with one hand), undated (Box 266)
        N# 0149
      - Man in the Shower 4, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0150
      - Richard in the Shower No. 5: Bending Over, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0151a
      - Richard in the Shower No. 9: Standing, 1978 (Box 266)
        N# 0152a
      - Nude with Weight Between His Legs, 1979 (Box 266)
        N# 0153a
      - Black Lace and Penis, 1979 (Box 266)
        N# 0154a
      - (nude on tiptoes with foot in sink-Jonathan Silin), undated (Box 266)
        N# 0155a
      - Crouching Nude with Motorcycle, 1977 (Box 266)
        N# 0156a
    - Balloon series
      - Male Nude with Balloons, circa 1974 (Box 267)
        N# 0165
      - Male Nude with Balloons, circa 1974 (Box 267)
        N# 0166
      - Male Nude with Balloons, circa 1974 (Box 267)
        N# 0167
      - Male Nude with Balloons, circa 1974 (Box 267)
        N# 0168
      - Male Nude with Balloons, circa 1974 (Box 267)
        N# 0169
      - Male Nude with Balloons, circa 1974 (Box 267)
        N# 0170
    - Neo-Classical series
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0279
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0280
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0281
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0282
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0283
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0284
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0285
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0286
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0287
      - Neo-Classical Self Portrait, 1974 (Box 268)
        P# 0288
    - Piano series
      - Self Portrait with Piano, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0289
      - Self Portrait with Piano, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0291
      - Self Portrait with Piano, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0292
      - Self Portrait with Piano, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0293
      - Self Portrait with Piano, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0294
      - Self Portrait with Piano, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0295
      - Self Portrait with Piano, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0296
    - Beach Sequence
      - Beach Sequence, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0297
      - Beach Sequence, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0298
      - Beach Sequence, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0299
      - Beach Sequence, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0300
      - Beach Sequence, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0301
      - Beach Sequence, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0302
      - Beach Sequence, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0303
      - Beach Sequence, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        P# 0304
    - Assorted nudes
      - Male and Female Nudes, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        N# 0157
      - Male and Female Nudes, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        N# 0158
      - Male and Female Nudes, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        N# 0159
      - Male and Female Nudes, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        N# 0160
      - Male and Female Nudes, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        N# 0161
      - Male and Female Nudes, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        N# 0162
      - Male and Female Nudes, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        N# 0163
      - Male and Female Nudes, circa 1974 (Box 269)
        N# 0164
- October 2011 Acquisition, 1988-2001; 2; 0.25; (1 box)
  Gift of Jonathan G. Silin, 2011.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1274.
  - Correspondence, writings of others, and printed materials, 1988-2001; 3 (Box 270)